## http://dansand.github.io

## DAN SANDIFORD

PHD. CANDIDATE

**Profile** 

I work with numerical models of the earth, including thermal convection in the mantle, plate motion and wave propagation.

Skills

Physical forward and inverse modelling

I use a range of community-driven software to model physical phenomena such as waves, fluids and heat flow. Data science

Skills in data wrangling, time series analysis and spatial statistics / mapping.

Field work

Experience conducting managing long-term field work projects.

Written communication

Find my articles at https://www.authorea.com/users/8456

Education

Bachelor of Arts/Science, Monash University

Geology/History/Mathematics

Bachelor of Science, (Honours), University of Melbourne

Seismology

PhD, (Honours), University of Melbourne

Geophysics - Geodynamics

**Technical** 

Python

R

Linux

Experience

Australian Geophysical Observing System

Field/Laboratory Assistant

2012-2013

2010-2012

2005-2010

2012-2013

2014-

Seismometer installation, maintenance. Petrophysical core logging, thermal properties testing, experimental design, equipment maintenance, reports.

Melbourne Energy Institute

Research Assistant

Promoting energy research, production of web and print publications, organisation of public seminar series.

Dan Sandiford — sandd@unimelb.edu.au